Guide to the Samuel R. Pierce papers, 1961-1985.
Pierce, Samuel R. papers
- Series XI. Awards and Gifts
  - City of Glen Cove - Citation to the Honorable Samuel R. Pierce, 1982 (Box 39)
  - Award: Key to the City of Greenville, South Carolina, No Date (Box 39)
  - Award: The American Jewish Heritage Committee Fund For a Better Tomorrow - The National Human Relations Award, 1986 (Box 39)
  - Award: County of Los Angeles - Appreciation, No Date (Box 40)
  - Resolution: Los Angeles - Commending Samuel Riley Pierce, Jr., 1984 (Box 40)
  - Award: The City of New Orleans - Honorary Citizen, 1985 (Box 40)
    2 Copies
  - Award: The City of Austin - Honorary Citizen, 1981 (Box 40)
  - Award: State of Indiana - Sagamore of the Wabash, 1981 (Box 40)
  - Sketch: Caricature of Samuel Pierce, Jr., No Date (Box 40)
  - Award: United States Department of the Treasury - Alexander Hamilton Award (See photo in box 34), 1973 (Box 41)
    Signed by Secretory George P. Shultz
  - Award: The Capital District Black Republican Council - Leadership, No Date (Box 41)
  - Award: The National Association of Home Builders - Appreciation, 1988 (Box 41)
  - Award: Black Methodist for Church Renewal - Recognition Award, 1983 (Box 42)
  - Award: Association of Minority Business Enterprises of New York - Outstanding Service Award, 1984 (Box 42)
  - Award: Mayor George V. Voinovich - The Corporate Seal of The City of Cleveland, 1983 (Box 43)
  - Award: The Martin Luther King, Jr. Center for Nonviolent Social Change, Inc. - Martin Luther King, Jr. Special Award, 1984 (Box 44)
  - Award: National Association of Real Estate Brokers, Inc. - Recognition of contribution, 1986 (Box 45)
  - Award: City of Los Angeles Mayor Tom Bradley - Recognition of leadership and support in Housing Programs, 1984 (Box 45)
  - Award: Boys and Girls Clubs of Greater Washington - F. Elwood Davis Award, 1987 (Box 46)
  - Coins: Numismatica Venezolana - Caciques de Venezuela, No Date (Box 46)
  - Gift from friends in Malmoe Sweden, No Date (Box 47)
  - Borough of Manhattan - Proclamation of "Samuel R. Pierce Day", 1987-11-20 (Box 48)
  - Award: Agudath Israel of America - 1988 Humanitarian Award, May 15, 1988 (Map-case DD-25)
  - Framed copy of H.R. 1158 with photograph of Ronald Reagan, January 19, 1989 (Map-case DD-25)
    Copy of the act that provided for the amendment of the 1968 Civil Rights Act to revise procedures for the enforcement of fair housing, and for other purposes. The frame also includes a photo of President Reagan with Pierce. The back states that this was presented to Pierce for his eight years of leadership in the campaign to guarantee equal housing opportunities for all Americans. It is from and signed by J. Michael Dorsey, John J. Knapp, Judith Y. Brachman, Antonio Monroig, Thomas D. Casey, Deborah Gore Dean, Lance H. Wilson, and one other.
  - Award: The Quarterback Club of Washington, D.C. (Trophy), 1988
  - Medals: The Department of Treasury - Secretaries of Treasury During Nixon Administration, No Date
    Richard Nixon, George P. Shultz, John B. Connally, David M. Kennedy
- Series XII. Scrapbooks
  - Scrapbook 1, 1970-71 (Box 8)
  - Scrapbook 2, 1971 (Box 8)
  - Scrapbook 3, 1971 (Box 8)
  - Scrapbook 4, 1972 (Box 8)
  - Scrapbook 5, 1972 (Box 8)
  - Scrapbook 6, 1973 (Box 8)
  - Scrapbook 7, 1973 (Box 8)
  - Scrapbook 8, 1974-95 (Box 8)
  - Scrapbook 9, 1976-77 (Box 8)
  - Scrapbook 10, 1977-78 (Box 8)
  - Scrapbook 11, 1978 (Box 8)
  - Scrapbook 12, 1979-80 (Box 8)
  - Scrapbook 13, 1980 (Box 9)
  - Scrapbook 14, 1981 (Box 9)
  - Scrapbook 15, 1981 (Box 9)
  - Scrapbook 16, 1981 (Box 9)
  - Scrapbook 17, 1981 (Box 9)
  - Scrapbook 18, 1981 (Box 9)
  - Scrapbook 19, 1981 (Box 9)
  - Scrapbook 20, 1981 (Box 9)
  - Scrapbook 21, 1982 (Box 9)
  - Scrapbook 22, 1982 (Box 10)
  - Scrapbook 23, 1982 (Box 10)
  - Scrapbook 24, 1982 (Box 10)
  - Scrapbook 25, 1982 (Box 10)
  - Scrapbook 26, 1982 (Box 10)
  - Scrapbook 27, 1982 (Box 10)
  - Scrapbook 28, 1982 (Box 10)
  - Scrapbook 29, 1982-83 (Box 10)
  - Scrapbook 30, 1983 (Box 10)
  - Scrapbook 31, 1983 (Box 10)
  - Scrapbook 32, 1983 (Box 11)
  - Scrapbook 33, 1983 (Box 11)
  - Scrapbook 34, 1983 (Box 11)
  - Scrapbook 35, 1983 (Box 11)
  - Scrapbook 36, 1983 (Box 11)
  - Scrapbook 37, 1983 (Box 11)
  - Scrapbook 38, 1984 (Box 11)
  - Scrapbook 39A, 1984 (Box 11)
  - Scrapbook 39, 1984 (Box 11)
  - Scrapbook 40, 1984 (Box 12)
  - Scrapbook 41, 1984 (Box 12)
  - Scrapbook 42, 1984 (Box 12)
  - Scrapbook 43, 1984 (Box 12)
  - Scrapbook 44, 1984 (Box 12)
  - Scrapbook 45, 1984 (Box 12)
  - Scrapbook 46, 1984 (Box 12)
  - Scrapbook 47, 1984 (Box 12)
  - Scrapbook 48, 1985 (Box 12)
  - Scrapbook 49, 1985 (Box 13)
  - Scrapbook 50, 1985 (Box 13)
  - Scrapbook 51, 1985 (Box 13)
  - Scrapbook 52, 1985-86 (Box 13)
  - Scrapbook 53, 1986 (Box 13)
  - Scrapbook 54, 1986 (Box 13)
  - Scrapbook 55, 1986 (Box 13)
  - Scrapbook 56, 1986-87 (Box 13)
  - Scrapbook 57, 1987 (Box 13)
  - Scrapbook 58, 1987 (Box 14)
  - Scrapbook 59, 1987 (Box 14)
  - Scrapbook 60, 1988 (Box 14)
  - Scrapbook 61, 1988 (Box 14)
  - Scrapbook 62, 1988 (Box 14)
  - Scrapbook 63, 1988-89 (Box 14)
  - Untitled Binder, No Date (Box 14)
  - General Counsel Opinions, 1970-74 (Box 14)
  - Samuel R. Pierce Binder, 1948-64 (Box 14)
  - Treasury Speeches and Remarks, 1970-77 (Box 14)
  - Photos of Certificates and Awards Folder, 1982-83 (Box 14)
  - Black Leather Scrapbook 1, 1964-65 (Box 15)
  - Black Leather Scrapbook 2, 1965-67 (Box 15)
  - Black Leather Scrapbook 3, 1967-68 (Box 15)
  - Black Leather Scrapbook 4, 1968-70 (Box 15)
  - Gray Binder Scrapbook 1 (A-G), 1981 (Box 15)
  - Gray Binder Scrapbook 2 (H-Mc), 1981 (Box 15)
  - Gray Binder Scrapbook (N-Z), 1981 (Box 15)
  - Treasury Speeches and Remarks Scrapbook (1-16), 1970-71 (Box 16)
  - Treasury Speeches and Remarks Scrapbook (17-32), 1970-71 (Box 16)
  - Photos of Awards and Certificates Scrapbook, 1943-1984 (Box 16)
  - "Miscellaneous Collectibles" Scrapbook, No Date (Box 16)
  - Samuel R. Pierce, Jr. Secretary of U.S. HUD 1982, 1982 (Box 17)
    Collection of photographs of events of the Secretary during 1982 by Dave Valdez
  - Scrapbook No. 955, The U.S. Department of Labor, 1956 (Box 17)
  - Citizens for the Republic proudly represents The Second Reagan Administration, No Date (Box 17)
  - Honorary Diploma - Glen Cove High School, 1982 (Box 17)
  - Interagency Agreement between HUD and Small Business Administration, 1982 (Box 17)
  - U.S. Industries, Inc. Certificate of Appreciation, 1970 (Box 17)
- Series XIII. Audio Cassettes, 1981-1988
  - Guest Speaker at the National Urban League 1981 Annual Conference, Plenary Session, 1981; 8916 (Box 29)
  - HUD Black History Month - Alex Haley (Guest), February 1981; 8917-8918 (Box 29)
  - News Conference, Economic Recovery (Budget Cuts), Washington, DC, March 1981; 8919-8921 (Box 29)
  - Meeting with Assistant Secretary Monroig at Fair Housing Ceremony, Washington, DC, April 1981; 8922-8923 (Box 29)
  - HUD Interview, Channel 7, Urban Update, Boston MA, April 1981; 8924 (Box 29)
  - HUD Eyewitness News Conference, WBZ-TB, Ch 4, Public Housing - Boston, Side 2, April 1981; 8925 (Box 29)
  - CBS Radio (Access Guest) with Teresa Ditore, May 1981; 8926-8927 (Box 29)
  - Mortgage Bankers Association, 68th Annual Convention, June 1981; 8928 (Box 29)
  - Management Meeting with HUD - Central Appointees (Budget Conscious), Washington, DC, June 1981; 8929 (Box 29)
  - Annual U.S. Conference of Mayors, Louisville, KY, June 1981; 8930-8933 (Box 29)
  - News Conference Announcing President's Commission, June 1981; 8934-8935 (Box 29)
  - 72nd NAACP Annual Convention, Denver, CO, June/July 1981; 8936 (Box 29)
  - National Association for the Advancement of Colorado People Convention, Denver, CO, July 1981; 8937 (Box 29)
  - Colorado Black Republican Council, Denver, CO, July 1981; 8938 (Box 29)
  - News Conference, Low Income Housing Construction, August 1981; 8939-8940 (Box 29)
  - National Town Meeting - Kennedy Center for Performing Arts, Washington, DC, October 1981; 8941-8943 (Box 29)
  - National Press Club Luncheon, October 1981; 8944-8945 (Box 29)
  - National Association of Realtors 74th Annual Convention, Miami, FL, November 1981; 8946 (Box 29)
  - Report to Employees, Four Sessions, Washington DC, December 1981; 8947-8951 (Box 29)
    Many duplicates, duplicates given tape recording number 8951
  - US News Interview with Mike Joan, 1982; 8952 (Box 29)
  - McNeil/Lehrer Report PBS, Urban Policy Report, 1982; 8953 (Box 29)
  - Hovde-Newman Report - Interview Conference, February 1982; 8954 (Box 29)
  - From Editors Desk (Answers Only), February 1982; 8955 (Box 29)
  - Working Group on Housing Policy, News Conference, April 1982; 8956 (Box 29)
  - Heritage Foundation, Chicago, IL, April 1982; 8957 (Box 29)
  - USA Today Economic Reporters Interview, April 1982; 8958 (Box 29)
  - Ottinger Seminar Rayburn, Washington, DC, April 1982; 8959 (Box 29)
  - Pennsylvania Black Republican Council, 20th Anniversary Dinner, Harrisburg, PA, June 1982; 8960 (Box 29)
  - Grant to Santa Cruz County, San Francisco, August 1982; 8961 (Box 29)
  - Blacks in Government, Inc., National Training Conference, Washington, DC, September 1982; 8962 (Box 29)
  - National Black Republican Council Mid-Term Convention, Washington, DC, September 1982; 8963 (Box 29)
  - Legislative Week, Enterprise Zone Workshop, Congressional Black Caucus, Washington, DC, September 1982; 8964 (Box 29)
  - Brooks Patterson Fundraiser, October 1982; 8965 (Box 29)
  - Groundbreaking for Three Housing Projects, Stamford, CT, October 1982; 8966 (Box 29)
  - Press Conference, Black Republican Advisory Group, Washington, DC, November 1982; 8967 (Box 29)
  - Providence Journal, Brown University, Public Affairs Conference, Providence, RI, November 1982; 8968 (Box 29)
  - Black Enterprise Interview, December 1982; 8969 (Box 29)
  - Press Conference, Federal Housing Authority Mortgage Insurance, December 1982; 8970 (Box 29)
  - National Newspaper Publishers Association Mid-Winter Workshop, Fort Lauderdale, FL, January 1983; 8971-8972 (Box 29)
  - U.S. Conference of Mayors, Washington, DC, January 1983; 8973 (Box 29)
  - Con. Housing Dereg. Sponsored by COC, NAHB, Foundation for Private Sector, January 1983; 8974 (Box 29)
  - Meeting with Congressmen on the Programs of Housing and Urban Development, February 1983; 8975 (Box 29)
  - Induction Ceremony, South Carolina Hall of Fame, Mary McLeod Bethune, February 1983; 8976 (Box 29)
  - Interview on Reagan Administration, Anti-Minority, etc., Los Angeles, CA, March 1983; 8977 (Box 29)
  - Cleveland City Club Forum, WCLV 95.5, Cleveland, OH, March 1983; 8978 (Box 29)
  - Interview with Alex Sullivan, KNX Radio, March 1983; 8979 (Box 29)
  - Press Conference on Urban Affairs Meeting on Ministerial Level, Paris, France, April 1983; 8980 (Box 29)
  - Senate Finance Committee on the Enterprise Zone Employment and Development act (S. 863), April 1983; 8981 (Box 29)
  - Interview with Clifford Evans, Profiles, WGMS-FM, April 1983; 8982 (Box 29)
  - Interview with Clifford Evans, Profiles, WGMS-FM, May 1983; 8983-8984 (Box 29)
  - Fair Housing Legislation - News Briefing, May 1983; 8985-8986 (Box 29)
  - Meeting with Steve Lambert, Marriott, Denver, Colorado, June 1983; 8987-8988 (Box 29)
  - Housing Authority Directors Association, Washington, DC, June 1983; 8989-8990 (Box 29)
  - Public Affairs council Conference, June 1983; 8991-8992 (Box 29)
  - Interview with Shirley Scheibla, Washington Editor, Barron's, September 1983; 8993 (Box 29)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology Center for Real Estate Development, September 1983; 8994 (Box 29)
  - (Hispanic Week, NW Plaza, December 1983; 8995 (Box 29)
  - Meeting with Governor Hal Sawyer and Dick Headlee, Michigan, 1984; 8996-8997 (Box 29)
  - National Fair Housing Campaign, Fort Worth, TX, February 1984; 8998 (Box 29)
  - Interview - AP Reuters, March 1984; 8999-9000 (Box 29)
  - Merrill Lynch Annual Housing Industry Seminar and Telephone Interview, New York, NY, March 1984; 9001-9002 (Box 29)
  - News Interview, March 1984; 9003-9004 (Box 29)
  - News Conference on the Fiscal Year 1986 Budget, Washington, DC, February 1985; 9005-9010 (Box 29)
  - Report to Employees (Morning and Afternoon Session), February 1985; 9011-9012 (Box 29)
  - News Conference on the Public Housing Home Ownership Demonstration, Washington, DC, June 1985; 9013 (Box 29)
  - Interview by Bill Celis, WSJ While at National Association of Home Builders Meeting, Dallas, TX, January 1985; 9014 (Box 29)
  - Secretary's Year-End Report to Employees, Washington, DC, January 1985; 9015-9017 (Box 29)
  - Press Briefing, April 1986; 9018 (Box 29)
  - Voice of America, U.S. Information Agency, Press Conference with Secretary Pierce, Washington, DC, May 1987; 9019 (Box 29)
  - Heritage Foundation, Washington DC, June 1988; 9020 (Box 29)
  - Howard University News Conference with President Cheek, No Date; 9021 (Box 29)
  - Narration on Housing and Urban Development Revolutionary Change/Economic Recovery, HUD Team, No Date; 9022 (Box 29)
  - "I Have a Dream" Speech by Martin Luther King, Jr., No Date; 9023 (Box 29)
- Series XIV. Video Cassettes, 1981-1988
  - Cable News Network with Secretary Pierce, August 1981; 5839 (Box 29)
  - Department of HUD, Secretary Pierce - Danish Interview (2731), Global Video, September 1981; 5840 (Box 29)
  - President's Commission on Executive Exchange, White House Cabinet Room, 1981; 5841 (Box 29)
  - Housing Affordability Press conference, Channel 5 News, WTTG with Pierce, January 1982; 5842 (Box 29)
  - From the Editor's Desk, Pierce - Housing, The Budget and Blacks, NYT Editorial board, February 1982; 5843 (Box 29)
  - Good Morning America, NBC Housing Series, April 1982; 5844 (Box 29)
  - McNeil Lehrer Report, Copy 1, July 1982; 5845 (Box 29)
  - McNeil Lehrer Report, Copy 2, July 1982; 5846 (Box 29)
  - McNeil Lehrer Report, Copy 3, July 1982; 5847 (Box 29)
  - CBS Morning News, September 1982; 5848 (Box 30)
  - Channel 4 News Congressman Henry Gonzalez Criticizes HUD, Secretary Pierce, September 1982; 5849 (Box 30)
  - McNeil/Lehrer Newshour, PBS, October 1982; 5852 (Box 30)
  - Today Show with Pierce, December 1982; 5850 (Box 30)
  - PBS Howard University, Evening Exchange, Sam Johnson, Host Interview, 1982; 5851 (Box 30)
  - Operation Build (HUD), KNBC News, LA, Archi Moore, August 1983; 5853 (Box 31)
  - C-SPAN Secretary Pierce, September 1983; 5854 (Box 31)
  - CBS Morning News Copy 1, December 1983; 5855 (Box 31)
  - CBS Morning News Copy 2, December 1983; 5856 (Box 31)
  - Alex J. Uri, Insight '93' WIXT/ABC, Syracuse, NY, 1983; 5857 (Box 31)
  - Live on WJLA-TV, Channel 6 News, February 1984; 5859 (Box 31)
  - Report on HUD, Secretary Pierce, CBS Evening News, February 1984; 5860 (Box 31)
  - Secretary Pierce Launches Fair Housing Campaign, Dallas, Texas, February 1984; 5861 (Box 31)
  - WFAA-TV, Question and Answer Interview, Dallas, TX, February 1984; 5862 (Box 31)
  - Samuel Pierce Addresses the Associated General Contractors in New Orleans, March 1984; 5863 (Box 31)
  - WABC-TV Eyewitness News, March 1984; 5864 (Box 31)
  - CBS Evening News - Dan Rather, April 1984; 5865 (Box 31)
  - National Press Club, John Fogarty, Host Luncheon Speaker, May 1984; 5902 (Box 31)
  - Secretary Pierce Reagan Endorsement, 1984; 5958 (Box 31)
  - McNeil/Lehrer News Hour Interview, 1984; 5903 (Box 31)
  - Fair Housing Ceremony: WNUC-TV, NYC; WXTV-Hispanic, Patterson, NY; WNJU-TV, 47 Hispanic, 1984; 5904 (Box 31)
  - PSA - Fair Housing, Secretary Pierce and Assistant Secretary Monroig Copy 1, 1984; 5905 (Box 31)
  - PSA - Fair Housing, Secretary Pierce and Assistant Secretary Monroig Copy 2, 1984; 5906 (Box 32)
  - PSA Fair Housing, Secretary Pierce and Assistant Secretary Monroig Copy 3, 1984; 5907 (Box 32)
  - Inaugural Gala Presidential Show Complete Performance, February 1985; 5908 (Box 32)
  - Republican Party Trying to Enroll Black Members, February 1985; 5909 (Box 32)
  - Samuel R. Pierce Jr. Press Club Speech, February 1985; 5910 (Box 32)
  - Secretary Pierce on Good Day, WCVB-TV, Boston, Copy 1, March 1985; 5911 (Box 32)
  - Secretary Pierce on Good Day, WCVB-TV, Boston, Copy 2, March 1985; 5912 (Box 32)
  - Small Business Report Enterprise Zone, March 1985; 5913 (Box 32)
  - Revolutionary Change at HUD, 1985; 5914 (Box 32)
  - HUD, Secretary Pierce at National Press Club, January 1987; 5915 (Box 32)
  - C-SPAN Senate Judiciary: "Fair Housing", March 1987; 5916 (Box 32)
  - Interview with HUD Secretary Samuel R. Pierce, Jr., Capital Hills Club, March 1987; 5917 (Box 32)
  - Secretary Samuel R. Pierce Jr. Council of 100, March 1987; 5918 (Box 32)
  - Secretary Pierce Interview on Modern Maturity Copy 1, September 1987; 5919 (Box 32)
  - Secretary Pierce Interview on Modern Maturity Copy 2, September 1987; 5920 (Box 32)
  - President Reagan Signs the Housing Bill at the White House, February 1988; 5921 (Box 32)
  - Radio-TV Monitoring Service, Inc. Ten O'Clock News WTTG-TV "Council of 100 Meeting", March 1988; 5922 (Box 32)
  - Swearing in Ceremony of Secretary Jack Kemp Department of HUD, 1989; 5923 (Box 32)
  - CBS - Lem Tucker's Interview with Pierce, No Date; 5924 (Box 32)
  - CH 5 Los Angeles "Transition House" and CH 7 Network "Night Line" "Homeless", No Date; 5925 (Box 32)
  - Miscellaneous Video Clips, No Date; 5926 (Box 32)
  - Today Show, NBC, Channel 4, No Date; 5927 (Box 32)
  - WRTV - Indianapolis, Probe of the HUD, No Date; 5928 (Box 32)
- Series XV. Miscellaneous Material
  - Response by Samuel R. Pierce, Jr. to Questionnaire for Prospective Nominees for United States Circuit Judgeship, Around 1975-80 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    Three copies
  - Biographical Documents, 1988 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - HUD Documents, 1981-89 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    New Directions in Housing and Urban Policy: 1981-1989, An Impact Evaluation of the Urban Development Action Grant Program, Working Partners, 1981 Annual Report
  - Battery Park City Documents, 1968 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Law Documents, 1965-73 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    10 Year Report Lawyer's Committee for Civil Rights Under Law, New York Times Co. v. Sullivan, Adolf I. Mayer v. Joseph T. Higgins, Howard Law Journal, The Institute for Civil Justice Annual Report, articles, Bar Association of Nassau County, NY, Inc. 89th Annual Dinner Pamphlet
  - Cornell Documents, 1988-2000 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    The Board of Trustees Calendar, mails, bills, Sphinx Head Newsletter, Cornell Law Forum
  - Harvard Documents, 1969-73 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    Board of Overseers of Harvard College: Committee Assignments
  - Pamphlets and Magazines, 1988-1991 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    Salute to Greatness 1989 dinner, Long Island Sports Hall of Fame Dinner of Champions, Compass, Emerging Trends in Real Estate: 1989, Constructor, 1991 Directory of Associates Telluride Association, Smart House, Institute of International Education
  - Books and Published Material (Box 33, Folder 9)
    Reagan's Ruling Class, The Autobiography of G. Gordon Liddy, U.S.S. Intrepid, A Decent Place to Live: The Report of the National Housing Task Force, The Journal of the Institute for Socioeconomic Studies, Cityscape: A Journal of Policy Development and Research, The Hoover Institution: Report 1984
  - Miscellaneous Documents (Box 33, Folder 10)
    The Heritage Lectures, Reagan's Report Card (article), Weekly Compilation of Presidential Documents, bills, receipts, invitations, informational catalogues, advertisements, a card containing names and numbers of the Treasury officials, Radio Corporation of America stock information booklet